（シアリーズ）オスカー…
Oscar...
（オスカー）君か シアリーズ
Seres.
（シアリーズ）一等対魔士の中でも
秀でた あなたが―
Imagine that, a praetor exorcist of your caliber being dispatched to this island.
この島へ派遣されるなんて
（オスカー）
アルトリウス様にとって―
Indeed, Lord Artorius considers this a very serious matter.
それだけ
大ごとということなのだろう
However...
しかし まさか 聖隷(せいれい)の君が
アルトリウス様を裏切るとはね
I never expected a malak like you to betray Lord Artorius.
驚いたよ
I'm quite shocked.
So you're the daemon-eater.
君が喰魔(くうま)か なるほど
I see.
（ベルベット）
船を奪い アルトリウスを討つ
I'm taking your ship, and I'm bringing Artorius down.
Your words deserve certain death.
万死に値する発言
Lord Artorius himself bestowed upon me this holy blade.
アルトリウス様より授かりし
我が退魔の剣 受けられるか
Think you can handle it?
You may be a daemon-eater,
but you're still a woman.
喰魔とはいえ 女性
We will treat you chivalrously...
礼は尽くさせてもらう…
So be it, insolent daemon.
無礼な業魔(ごうま)と覚えておこう
I am Oscar Dragonia, a praetor exorcist from the Abbey in the sacred kingdom of Midgand.
我が名は ミッドガンド聖導王国
聖寮(せいりょう)一等対魔士―
オスカー･ドラゴニア
アルトリウス様の命により
お前を拘束する！
I will subdue you as per Lord Artorius's orders.
ふんっ！
はあっ！ うっ！ ふんっ！
（オスカー）まるで獣だな
You are a beast indeed.
だが 私が来た以上
君に勝機はない
However, as long as I'm here, there's no way you can win.
Your ferocity almost made me forget why I'm here.
君の獰猛(どうもう)さに
目的を忘れてしまいそうだ
こんな果てまで
私がやって来たのは―
I didn't come all this way to kill you.
君を殺すためではない
You will return to the prison.
もといた牢獄に戻ってもらうよ
君の役割は
業魔を食べ続けることだ
Your purpose is to continue devouring daemons...
喰魔よ
Daemon-eater.
（ベルベット）私は あの男を
殺すためだけに生きてきた
The only reason I live is to see that man dead.
I've devoured daemons day in and day out.
来る日も 来る日も
業魔を喰(く)い続けて
And to what end?
それが いかなる理由であろうとも
（オスカー）
それが憎いというのなら 間違いだ
Your hatred for us is unfounded.
それこそが 君の役割
That is your role.
The world has deemed it so.
世界が示した ことわりだ
The same way it deemed my brother's role was to be a sacrifice?!
私の弟を生贄(いけにえ)にしたようにか
そうだ
Yes.
Every person has a role in life.
誰にも
役割というものがあるのだよ
Lord Artorius was the one who showed that to the world.
あの方 アルトリウス様は
それを世界に示されたのだ
（ベルベット）誰かの命を
引き換えにした世界なんて―
A world that sacrifices people's lives?
I cannot abide that.
私は許さない
I don't care what happens to this world,
この世界が どうなろうが―
if it was built on the sacrifice of my brother's life.
私の弟を生贄にして
作った世界など―
I will never...
絶対に―
許さない！
stand for it!
Then I suppose you won't return to your cell willingly.
おとなしく 牢獄に
戻ってはもらえないようだな
What is that?
（シアリーズ）あれは…
（オスカー）ドラゴン
A dragon.
It's the first time I've seen one too.
私も見るのは初めてだ
（シアリーズ）あれが…
So that's...
But what's a dragon doing here?
しかし なぜ
こんなところにドラゴンが
喰魔か
The daemon-eater?
It's coming! Shoot it!
来るぞ！ 迎え撃て！
（オスカー）おのれ 業魔が！
Damn that daemon!
I can't believe that's a daemon!
（シアリーズ）
あれが業魔なんて信じられない
信じようと信じまいと
これは真実だ！
Whether you believe it or not, it's here!
In the end, that is what becomes of human malevolence.
あれは 人の穢(けが)れの行く末だ
That's why Lord Artorius created this world.
だから アルトリウス様は
この世界をお作りになられた
That reasoning is...
（シアリーズ）そんな理屈！
Here it comes!
来たぞ！
You monster!
（オスカー）この化け物が！
After seeing this, do you still doubt Lord Artorius, Seres?!
この様を見て―
まだ アルトリウス様に
異を唱えるか シアリーズ！
I have no intention of living under someone else's ideals.
（シアリーズ）私は 誰かの理想の
庇護(ひご)のもとで生きるつもりはない！
私は―
I...
will follow my own path.
私の道を生きる！
Don't make me laugh.
（オスカー）笑えるよ
Such words ring hollow, coming from you!
それを 仮にも
君が言葉にするとはな！
The remaining ship...
残る船は…
（マギルゥ）誰じゃあ？
わしの安眠を邪魔したのは
Who dares disturb my slumber?
いやはや わびもなしかぇ？
What?
Not even an apology?
何じゃの 主らは？
What's the matter with you people?
I was having such a pleasant nap.
スヤッと安眠しとるわしを
起こしおってからに
And I thought I'd died and gone to hell!
まさに 極楽から地獄ー！
And it was a prison hell!
と思ったら マジ 牢獄じゃしー
Then I thought I escaped prison, and this time, we're sinking?!
牢獄を抜け出したと思ったら
今度は沈没かやー？
Can you understand my misery?
この切なさ… 分かるじゃろ？
Hear me!
（マギルゥ）
よーく聞けー！ わしこそは―
I have traveled the world and more!
八紘四界(はっこうしかい)を股にかけ
ドラゴンも笑う大魔法使ーい！
Dragons are trifling things to me, the great sorceress!
ぬっ おにょにょ ななっ
ど… どこへ行くんじゃあ？
H-Hey, where are you going?!
Now's my chance to commandeer the ship and escape.
今のうちに船を奪い 脱出する
If the ship gets destroyed, I won't be able to get off the island.
船を壊されたら
島を出られなくなる
That would be bad!
それは困るのう！
我が聖隷よ！
Heed my call, malak!
The barrier...
結界が…
くそっ
Dammit!
I'll take him on!
やってやる
（ベルベット）こんなところで
立ち止まるわけにはいかない
I won't let anything stop me here.
あいつを倒すまで！
Not until I bring that bastard down.
（シアリーズ）ベルベット･クラウ
Velvet Crowe.
There's only one way to get out of this predicament and reach Artorius.
この窮地を脱し アルトリウスを
倒す方法は１つしかありません
I'm going to bet my life on you!
この命 あなたに懸けます
What?
なに？
It's using an arte?!
術を使うだと！
（マギルゥ）困ったのう
Well, now I'm in a bind.
よく考えたら わしは
船の動かし方を知らんのじゃ
Come to think of it, I don't know how to sail a ship.
So I can't let you eat her.
よって あやつを
喰わせるわけにいかぬ
（ロクロウ）俺は ロクロウ
I'm Rokurou, and I need a ship too.
俺も船が必要でな
So allow me to assist you.
よって 助太刀する
（マギルゥ）おおー！
ロクロウとやら 頼むぞ！
Rokurou, huh? All right, I'm counting on you!
Hear me!
よく聞けい！
我こそは 大魔法使い
その名も―
I am the great sorceress!
Mazhigigika Miludin do Din Nolurun Dou!
マジギギカ･ミルディン･
ド･ディン･ノルルン･ドゥ！
略してマギルゥと 覚えおけーい！
Also known as Magilou! And don't you forget it!
Why?
どうして…
（シアリーズ）全ては
アルトリウスを打倒するため
It is all to bring down Artorius.
あなたなら…
You can...
私を 食べてください
Please devour me.
何を言っている？
What are you saying?
I am under a contract that binds my powers with my own life.
（シアリーズ）私には
命を捧げることを枷(かせ)にした―
誓約が かかっています
私を喰らって
力を手に入れてください
Devour me and take my powers.
前に進むための力を
The power to move forward.
Why would you go so far?
どうして ここまでする
私の心にもあるのです
Like you, a fire burns in my heart.
あなたと同じ
消したくても消せない炎が
A fire that I cannot extinguish no matter how hard I try.
ラフィのくし…
Laphi's comb?
（シアリーズ）
早く 私の命が尽きないうちに
Please hurry... before my life ends.
（ベルベット）
礼も謝罪も言わないから
I won't thank you or apologize.
（シアリーズ）必要ありません
There is no need.
私の望みも…
It is my wish too.
ハァ… ハァ… ぐっ
うりゃあっ！
（ロクロウ）うらああっ！
こりゃあ… ちと ヤバいかのう
This isn't good.
That arte... It can't be!
（オスカー）あの術は まさか…
You devoured Seres?!
喰ったのか シアリーズを！
悪く思うな！
I'm sorry,
but I cannot let a monster like you loose on the world!
お前のような化け物を
世に放つわけにはいかないのだ！
It's Velvet.
（ベルベット）ベルベットよ
（オスカー）あっ…
That's my name.
（ベルベット）私の名前
アルトリウスに告げなさい
Make sure Artorius knows.
私は ベルベット･クラウ
I am Velvet Crowe!
業魔も 聖隷も 対魔士も
喰らい尽くす―
Daemons, malakim, exorcists... I will devour them all!
最悪の―
I am the daemon-eater...
who'll bring calamity!
喰魔だ！
風が出てきたな
The wind is picking up.
お二人！ どこを目指すよ？
You two! Where shall we go?
どこでも かまわぬぞー
Anywhere is fine with me!
なりゆきのまま 風に乗って
フラフラじゃあ
I go where the wind takes me!
（ロクロウ）うむ
（ベルベット）
ねえ ラフィは知ってる？
Do you know, Laphi?
何で 鳥が空を飛ぶか
Why do birds fly across the skies?
そうじゃないと
エサが取れないからだよ
They have to fly in order to find food.
And to escape from predators.
敵からも逃げられないし
（ベルベット）フフッ だよねえ
That's true.
（ラフィ）でも 僕は思うんだ
But you know what I think?
翼を持った鳥は…
Birds with wings...
にいさん…
Brother...
What are you doing?
何を言って…
（アルトリウス）
これが 現実のことわりだ
This is the true way of things.
And I, the exorcist Artorius
Collbrande, shall stop the pain.
この痛みは―
対魔士 アルトリウス･
コールブランドが止める
アルトリウスー！！
Artorius!
（ベルベット）
ミッドガンド領に舵を
Set sail for Midgand.
王都 ローグレスを目指す
The royal capital...
Logress is my destination.
どうなるか 分からんが
それも人生の醍醐味(だいごみ)じゃて
I have no idea what lies ahead,
but that's what makes life interesting.
Violent winds, people standing stock-still
Rise, ye of wandering hearts
Justice in fetters, a sorrow ringing without cease,
Can't take that next step forward
Bury those tears clouding your vision
Hope that claws its way out of the darkness will be all the more radiant
It's a brilliant, brand new day
Dash through and go ahead on your way
Light your extraordinary life ablaze
Your uncertainty, take it all away
Come all what may, just believe your way
That field called the world
With light emitted with all your heart,
Brand it with your searing emotions
Next Time
...
Velvet
What's wrong? We're free, so why the long face?
Rokurou
That dragon was a formidable opponent.
Velvet
Yeah, that was scary.
Rokurou
It commanded such destructive force.
Magilou
...
All
Let's be optimistic! We're about to go out into the world!
Rokurou
You're right!
Magilou
Next week: "To Each His Own Thoughts."
Velvet
Oh, that's a fitting title.
Magilou
I'll say! Velvet has her own thoughts, and I have mine.
Rokurou
Me too! So we're starting an adventure, each with our own goals!
Magilou
Damn, I'm excited!
Rokurou
I can't wait for what's ahead!
Magilou
Unfortunately, we don't have any scenes.
Velvet
Are you serious?! Why not?
Magilou
Then who's on next week?!
Rokurou
I dunno. But whoever appears will no doubt have their own goals and battles.
Velvet